Kael mss., 1939-2001 LMC 3004
Lilly Library
- V. Subjects
  - African-Americans and film, (6 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 99)
  - Animation, (2 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 99)
  - Censorship and Obscenity, (3 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 99)
  - Comedy, (2 folders) (Box 99)
  - Critics: (Box 100)
    - Agee, James (Box 100)
    - Green, Graham (Box 100)
    - Hobson, Harold (Box 100)
    - MacDonald, Dwight (Box 100)
    - Sarris, Andrew (Box 100)
    - Tynan, Kenneth (Box 100)
    - General, (2 folders) (Box 100)
  - Detective, (see also: Box 120) (Box 100)
  - Film - General, 1940s-2000s, (10 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 100)
  - Film lists: (Box 100)
    - Academy Awards (Box 100)
    - All-Time Rental Champs, 1981-1993, (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - New York Film Releases (Box 100)
    - Various (Box 100)
  - Film theory (Box 100)
  - Horror, Science Fiction, Gangster (Box 100)
  - MGM., Photographs from various movies (Box 100)
  - Music - Jazz (Box 100)
  - Music - Scores (Box 100)
  - Musicals (Box 100)
  - New Yorker, (2 folders) (Box 101)
  - Political - HUAC and U.S. blacklist (Box 101)
  - Political - general (Box 101)
  - Regions: (Box 101)
    - Africa (Box 101)
    - Asia, (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - Australia/New Zealand, (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - Canada, (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - Czechoslovakia, (see also: Box 120) (Box 101)
    - France, (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - Germany, (3 folders) (Box 101)
    - Great Britain (Box 101)
    - Greece (Box 101)
    - Holland (Box 101)
    - Hungary (Box 101)
    - India (Box 101)
    - Israel (Box 101)
    - Italy (Box 101)
    - Japan, (4 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 101)
  - Regions: (Box 102)
    - Latin America & Caribbean, (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - Poland (Box 102)
    - Russia (Box 102)
    - Scandinavia, (2 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 102)
    - Spain (Box 102)
    - Switzerland (Box 102)
    - Yugoslavia (Box 102)
    - Various (Box 102)
  - Reviews: (Box 102)
    - Art, Music, Theatre, (see also: Box 120) (Box 102)
    - Books, (4 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 102)
    - Film, 1926-1998; (14 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 102)
  - Reviews: (Box 103)
    - Film, 1999-2001; (6 folders) (Box 103)
  - Screenwriters/writers: (Box 103)
    - Baldwin, James, (2 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
    - Colette, (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
    - Faulkner, William, (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
    - Goldman, Bo (Box 103)
    - Goldman, William (Box 103)
    - Greene, Graham, (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
    - Guare, John (Box 103)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
    - James, Clive (Box 103)
    - Loos, Anita, (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - Mailer, Norman (Box 103)
    - O'Neill, Eugene, (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
    - Simon, Neil (Box 103)
    - Vidal, Gore, (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
    - Westlake, Donald (Box 103)
    - Various, (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
  - Shorts, (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
  - Silent movies., (2 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 103)
  - Television (cont.), (6 folders) (Box 104)
  - Violence (Box 104)
  - Visual literacy (Box 104)
  - Walt Disney Productions, (see also: Box 120) (Box 104)
  - Westerns (Box 104)
  - Women and film, (6 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 104)
  - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (see also: Box 120) (Box 104)
  - Articles concerning Kael, 1960-1990s (Box 117 Oversize)
  - Articles concerning Kael, 1980s-1990s (Box 122 Oversize)
  - Subjects: Actors. A - G (Box 118 Oversize)
  - Subjects: Actors. H - Z (Box 119 Oversize)
  - Subjects: African-Americans and film - Z (Box 120 Oversize)
- VI. Memorabilia
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Addresses and telephone numbers., (5 folders) (Box 104)
  - Awards (Box 104)
    - The American Academy of Arts and Letters award in Literature., 1970, May 26; Notification, program and exhibition catalog (Box 104)
    - George Polk Memorial Award for Criticism for 1970., 1971, Mar. 24; Program, plaque (Box 104)
    - The National Book National Book Award for arts and letters. "A Celebration of Letters: The Twenty-Fifth Anniversary of the National Book Awards", 1974, Apr. 18; (see also: Box 123) (Box 104)
    - Newswomen's Club of New York, Inc., Front Page Award for Best Magazine Column., 1974, Nov. 22; Program and citation (Box 104)
  - Awards (cont.) (Box 105)
    - Women in Film., 1978; (see: Box 108 and Box 123) (Box 105)
    - Phi Beta Kappa certificate from Radcliffe College., 1982, June 8 (Box 105)
    - Newswomen's Club of New York, Inc., Front Page Award for Distinguished Journalism., 1983; Plaque (Box 105)
    - Mel Novikoff Award, accepted on Kael's behalf by Michael Sragow at the 34th San Francisco International Film Festival., 1991, May 2; (see also: Box 109) (Box 105)
    - Los Angeles Film Critics Association, annual achievement awards, special award accepted by Marcia Nasatir for Kael., 1995, Jan. 17; (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - The Independent Feature Project Gotham Award., 1995, Sept. 19; (see also: Box 108) (Box 105)
    - PEN Center, USA West, literary award for Body of Work in Criticism., 1996, Oct. 26; (see also: Box 108) (Box 105)
    - The National Book Critics Circle's Ivan Sandrof Award for Contribution to American Arts & Letters., 1999; Plaque (Box 105)
  - Calendars. New Yorker calendars, 1985-1991; Annotated with titles of films reviewed by Kael (Box 105)
  - Film critics awards, 1972-1990; (2 folders) (Box 105)
  - Film festivals., Mostly printed programs. Arranged alphabetically by location or title of festival: (Box 105)
    - Animation Film Festival in New York, 2nd International, 1974 (Box 105)
    - Asian American International Film Festival. 1984; 1986 (Box 105)
    - Berlin Internationale Filmfestspiele. 1999 (Box 105)
    - Cannes, Festival International du Film. 6th, 1953; 30th, 1977, including materials concerning her service as a jury member (Box 105)
    - Chicago International Film Festival. 1963, Kael's notes only; 1st, 1965; 7th, 1971 (program and reviews); 8th, 1972; 9th, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - Denver International Film Festival. 4th, 1981 (Box 105)
    - Edinburgh International Film Festival. 1984; 40th, 1986 (Box 105)
    - The Hawai'i International Film Festival, 1985 (Box 105)
    - Los Angeles International Film Exposition. 1st, 1971; 2nd, 1972; 1974; 1975; 1976; 1982; 1983, (5 folders) (Box 105)
    - Montreal Festival International du Film. 1965; 6th, 1980 (Box 105)
  - Film Festivals (cont.), (see also: Boxes 81 and 120) (Box 106)
    - New York Film Festival. 1st, 1963; 2nd, 1964; 3rd, 1965; 5th, 1967; 6th, 1968; 7th, 1969; 8th, 1970; 9th, 1971; 10th, 1972; 12th, 1974; 13th, 1975; 16th, 1978; 23rd, 1985; 24th, 1986; 25th, 1987; 31st, 1993; 34th, 1996, (3 folders) (Box 106)
    - Palm Springs International Film Festival, 1992 (Box 106)
    - Paris Festival Cinematographique International. 4th, 1977 (Box 106)
    - San Diego International Film Festival. 3rd, 1980; 1981 (Box 106)
    - San Francisco International Film Festival. 5th, 1961; 9th, 1966; 41st, 1998; 42nd, 1999, (see also: Box 120) (Box 106)
    - San Sebastian Festival Internacional de Cine. 37th, 1989 (Box 106)
    - Seattle Film Festival. 9th, 1984; 12th, 1987 (Box 106)
    - Toronto Festival of Festivals. 1979; 1980; 1984, (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - Vancouver. 1959; 1962 (Box 106)
  - Film series., (3 folders) (see also: Box 123 and series III. Writings. Film series); emph: Cinema 16,; emph: Film Forum, (Box 106)
  - Honorary degrees (Box 106)
    - Georgetown University, Doctor of Laws, honoris causa., 1972, May 21; (see also: Box 123) (Box 106)
    - Columbia College (Chicago, Illinois), Doctor of Arts and Letters., 1972, June 8; Diploma (Box 106)
    - Smith College, Doctor of Letters., 1973, May 27; Program, diploma (Box 106)
    - Kalamazoo College, Doctor of Humane Letters. Program; Kalamazoo College Bulletin, June, 1973., 1973, June 9; diploma (Box 106)
    - Haverford College, Doctor of Humane Letters., 1975, May 13; (see also: Box 123) (Box 106)
    - Reed College, Doctor of Humane Letters., 1975, May 18; (see also: Box 123) (Box 106)
    - Allegheny College, Honorary Doctor of Letters., 1979, June 11; Program, diploma (Box 106)
    - School of Visual Arts, New York City, Doctorate of Fine Arts, 1980, June 19; (see: Box 123) (Box 106)
  - Lectures/speeches, etc., (2 folders) (see also: Box 124) (Box 107)
  - Legal. Pauline Kael/Warren Beatty Agreement., 1979 (Box 107)
  - Medical., Glasses prescription, 1970; medical diagnoses 1990, 2001 (Box 107)
  - Memorial service., Printed memorial; copies of remarks made by David Edelstein, daughter Gina James and Craig Seligman (Box 107)
  - National Arts Journalism Program-Columbia University Distinguished Lectureship in Criticism., (2 folders) (Box 107)
  - The New Yorker., (see also: Box 108) (Box 107)
  - Pauline Kael's Library on Film., April 2001 (Box 107)
  - Photographs, (see also: Boxes 120 and 123) (Box 107)
    - Boyars, Marion., (3) (Box 107)
    - Brantley, Will., (1) (Box 107)
    - Publicity shots of Kael, (25) (Box 107)
    - Ritz, Harry., (2); (2 and 2 negatives) (Box 107)
    - Snapshots of Kael, (6) (Box 107)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, (16) (Box 107)
  - Short films., Lists/ballots, 1974-1980 (Box 107)
  - Theater programs., Designed by Jess [Collins] (Box 107)
  - Travel., Itineraries, airline boarding passes, hotel receipts and invoices (Box 107)
  - Miscellaneous., Includes: two White House Festival of the Arts programs, June 14, 1965; items relating to daughter Gina; various receipts (Box 107)
  - Awards (Box 108: Realia)
    - Women in Film., 1978; Award - engraved glass (Box 108: Realia)
    - The Independent Feature Project Gotham Award., 1995, Sept. 19; Award - Lucite on wood base with embedded representation of the Empire State Building (Box 108: Realia)
    - PEN Center,..., 1996, Oct. 26; Award - engraved Lucite (Box 108: Realia)
  - The New Yorker., Lengthy scroll of brown paper with attached poems written by co-workers when Kael left for Hollywood in 1979 (Box 108: Realia)
  - Awards (Box 109: Realia)
    - Mel Novikoff Award., 1991, May 2; Award - engraved, gold-plated 35mm reel (Box 109: Realia)
  - Film Festivals (Box 120: Oversize)
    - San Francisco International Film Festival. 34th, 1991; 35th, 1992; 37th, 1994; 38th, 1995, (2 folders) (Box 120: Oversize)
  - Photographs (Box 120: Oversize)
    - Kael's 80th birthday group photograph, (2) (Box 120: Oversize)
  - Awards (Box 123: Oversize folio)
    - The National Book Award., 1974, Apr. 18; Citation (Box 123: Oversize folio)
    - Women in Film., 1978; Citation; program (Box 123: Oversize folio)
  - Film series (Box 123: Oversize folio)
    - Poster for "The Critics' Choices of the Great Films," Unicorn Cinema, La Jolla, CA., undated (after 1972) (Box 123: Oversize folio)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 123: Oversize folio)
    - Georgetown University,..., 1972, May 21; Diploma (Box 123: Oversize folio)
    - Haverford College,..., 1975, May 13; Diploma (Box 123: Oversize folio)
    - Reed College,..., 1975, May 18; Diploma (Box 123: Oversize folio)
    - School of Visual Arts,..., 1980, June 19; Diploma (Box 123: Oversize folio)
  - Photographs (Box 123: Oversize folio)
    - Girls' High School, San Francisco, Class of June 1936, accompanied by letter from Rose Makower (Box 123: Oversize folio)
  - Lectures/speeches, etc. (Box 124: Oversize folio)
    - Posters for: The University of California Bicentennial Committee, Apr. 1, 1976; California institute of the Arts, Valencia, California, Mar. 27, 1978; Regis College, Weston, Massachusetts, Oct. 26, 1987 (Box 124: Oversize folio)
- VII. Audiovisual
  Arranged by format: reel-to-reel audiotapes, audio cassettes and one 16mm film. May not be used in present formats.
  - KPFA (Box 110)
    - 7" reel-to-reel audiotapes., May 1961-Apr. 1962; (26 tapes) (Box 110)
    - 10" reel-to-reel audiotapes., undated; (2 tapes) (Box 110)
  - Mobile Film Show., 7" reel-to-reel audiotapes (Box 110)
    - 1. Woody Allen, Mar. 20, 1974; (4 tapes) (Box 110)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Available electronically through Indiana University's Media Collections Online.
      40000002862599
      Pauline Kael w/ Woody Allen
      40000002862730
      Pauline Kael w/ Woody Allen 1/2 hour version
      40000002862581
      The Pauline Kael Show w/ Woody Allen Pt. 1
      40000002862664
      The Pauline Kael Show w/ Woody Allen Pt. 2
    - 2. Francis Ford Coppola, Mar. 1974; (4 tapes) (Box 110)
    - 3. Steven Spielberg, undated; (1 tape) (Box 110)
    - 4. Peter Bogdanovich, undated; (1 tape) (Box 110)
    - 5. Martin Scorsese, undated; (1 tape) (Box 110)
  - KPFA (Box 111)
    - 10" reel-to-reel audiotapes., Aug. 1954-Oct. 1963; (13 tapes) (Box 111)
    - Compact discs, May 1961-Mar. 27, 1963; (4 discs and 4 copies) (Box 111)
  - Unidentified (Box 111)
    - 7" reel-to-reel audiotapes., undated; (6 tapes) (Box 111)
  - Miscellaneous reel-to-reel audiotapes., 7", undated, one tape per title, unless otherwise indicated (Box 112)
    - 10 Days, (2 tapes) (Box 112)
    - 2001: Science Fiction or Man's Future, May 7, 1970; (2 tapes) (Box 112)
    - Albert Singing (Box 112)
    - As it Happens for Curr Aff (Exorcist) (Box 112)
    - The Band Wagon: Triplets Soft Shoe Number (Box 112)
    - The Beggar's Opera (Box 112)
    - Capriccio (Box 112)
    - Citizen Kane's Oscar, May 22, 1969; 5" reel-to-reel (Box 112)
    - [Cosmo pictures, Raymond F. Gardner], 5" reel-to-reel (Box 112)
    - Film: Pauline Kael and Robert Altman (Box 112)
    - Hud (Box 112)
    - Interview with critics Mitchell Lipton and Wesley Day, July 4 and July 5, 1961 (Box 112)
    - Kael-Lipton (Box 112)
    - Marvin Tartak: Recital, (5" tape) (Box 112)
    - Movies: Art or Awful (Box 112)
    - Music for "Caligari" (Box 112)
    - Nosferatu (Box 112)
    - Orpheus in Sausalito (Box 112)
    - Pauline Kael on the movie A Taste of Honey (Box 112)
    - Role of the Critic (Box 112)
    - Torre-Nilsson (Box 112)
  - Audio cassettes (Box 112)
    - Books on Tape: State of the Art, 1992; (15 tapes) (Box 112)
    - Close Encounters of the Third Kind—reviewed Nov. 17, 1977, KTNQ (Box 112)
    - Cosmo picture, Raymond F. Gardner, Norwich, Vt. (Box 112)
    - Grover Sales, Robert Towne, Apr. 1977; (1 tape) (Box 112)
    - On Movies, Pauline Kael, #439, June 1982 (Box 112)
    - Pauline Kael Memorial, Nov. 30, 2001; (1 tape) (Box 112)
    - Rosebud in the Snow, Dec. 24, 1991 (Box 112)
    - Sam Peckinpah Memorial, 1984 (Box 112)
    - Talia ______ Johnson, undated; (1 tape) (Box 112)
    - The Talk of Vermont with Jeff Kaufman, undated (Box 112)
    - Untitled, undated, from David Chasman, (1 tape) (Box 112)
  - 16mm film (Box 112)
    - Promotion clip for The New Yorker with scene from Citizen Kane, Feb. 24, 1971 (Box 112)